A Guide to the Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Associates, Harper Woodward FA1227
Rockefeller Archive Center
Laurance S. Rockefeller papers, Associates, Harper Woodward
1946-1981
Rockefeller Archive Center
Rockefeller, Laurance Spelman (1910-2004)
Woodward, Harper
FA1227
7.58 Cubic Feet 15 letter document boxes and 4 legal document boxes
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Biographical / Historical
Harper Woodward was born in Rochester, New York in 1909. A graduate of Harvard College in 1931 and Harvard Law School 1934, he spent one year as Secretary to President James B. Conant of Harvard, then became a practicing attorney in New York City and Rochester, specializing in aviation matters.
During World War II, Woodward attained the rank of Lt. Colonel in the United States Air Force. From 1943-1945, he served as a member of the Advisory Council to the General of the Army H. H. Arnold.
Following the war, Woodward was appointed Director of the Aviation Division, Surplus Property Administration in Washington, DC. He joined Rockefeller Family and Associates in May 1946.
Woodward was a Director of Eastern Airlines, Itek Corporation, GAB Business Services, Inc., Caneel Bay Plantation, Inc., Coherent Radiation, Mauna Kea Beach Hotel Corporation, Rockresorts, Inc., and the Wings Club. He served as Vice President and member of the Board of Managers of Memorial Hospital; Vice Chairman of the Executive Committee of the Hospital; and a member of the Board of Trustees of Memorial Sloan-Kettering Cancer Center and of Sloan-Kettering Institute for Cancer Research.
Woodward was also a member of the American Yacht Club and the Mansuring Island Club (both in Rye, NY) and the Metropolitan Club (in Washington, D.C.).
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, memos and reports primarily pertaining to Eastern Airlines and other aviation interests, Memorial Hospital, Sloan-Kettering Institute and Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center.
Records also document the institutions and foundations for which Harper Woodward served as a Board or Club member, as well as reports and analysis of various investments made by or on behalf of Laurance S. Rockefeller.
- General Files, 1946-1981; 1; 5.32 Cubic Feet 14 letter document boxes
  - A-C, 1979-1981 (Box 1, Folder 1-7)
  - Caneel Bay, 1974-1978 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Christ's Church, 1955-1978 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Civil Aeronautics, 1975-1978 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - D-E, 1979-1981 (Box 2, Folder 4-5)
  - Eastern Airlines, 1968-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Eastern Airlines, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 1-4, Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Eastern Airlines - Cab Investigation, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Eastern Airlines - National Merger, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 3-4)
  - Erb, Richard L., 1975-1977 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - F, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - G, 1967-1980 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - H, 1960-1980 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Harvard, 1948-1980 (Box 5, Folder 3-4)
  - Harvard Law School, 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Harvard Overseers Committee, 1955-1960 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Harvard Class of 1931 - 50th Reunion, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Hemisphere Club, 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - I, 1961-1981 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Itek, 1977-1980 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - J, 1963-1980 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - K, 1973-1980 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Memos - Laurance S. Rockefeller to Harper Woodward, 1949-1970 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - L, 1972-1980 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Little Dix, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - M, 1952-1980 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Manursing Island Club, 1948-1978 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Mauna Kea, 1961-1978 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center (MSKCC), 1977-1981 (Box 7, Folder 4-5, Box 8, Folder 1-4, Box 9, Folder 1-3)
  - Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center (MSKCC) - Articles of Incorporation and By-Laws (Box 9, Folder 4-5)
  - Sloan Kettering Institute - Annual Report, 1978 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center (MSKCC) - Contributions - Rockefeller family and Related Organizations, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center (MSKCC) - Fundraising, 1977-1979 (Box 10, Folder 3-4)
  - Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center (MSKCC) - General Motors, 1949-1973 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center (MSKCC) - Organizational Planning Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - N, 1959-1980 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - O-Q, 1966-1980 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - R, 1970-1980 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Rockefeller Center, Inc., 1975 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Rockefeller - Joint Office Reports, 1964-1980 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Rockefeller Center Luncheon Club, 1977-1980 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Laurance S. Rockefeller (LSR), 1974-1980 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Rockresorts, 1978-1980 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - S, 1957-1980 (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
  - Securities and Exchange Commission (SEC), 1979 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - St. Paul's School, 1952-1980 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Harper Woodward Speech Material and Speeches, 1950s-1960s (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - T, 1979-1980 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Trusteeship, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - U, 1966-1980 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Venrock, 1969-1978 (Box 13, Folder 2-3)
  - Venrock - Correspondence, 1968-1980 (Box 13, Folder 4-5)
  - Venrock - Venture Capital Reports, 1946-1980 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - W, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Wings Club, 1968-1980 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Wayfarer, 1959-1981 (Box 14, Folder 3-4)
  - Z, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 5)
- Reports, 1946-1980; 2; 2.26 Cubic Feet 4 legal document boxes and 1 letter document box
  - Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center (MSKCC) - Corporate Development Committee Reports, 1977-1979 (Box 15, Folder 1-3)
  - Memorial Sloan Kettering Cancer Center (MSKCC) - Fundraising, 1977-1978 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Eastern Airlines - Financial Profile, 1979 May (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Eastern Airlines - Program Review, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Eastern Airlines - Products and Services, 1977 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports, 1978-1979 (Box 16, Folder 3-5, Box 17, Folder 1-3)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes annual reports of Alfred P. Sloan Foundation, Eastern Airlines, General Motors Cancer Research Foundation, Sloan-Kettering Institute, McDonald's Corporation and Community Programs, MSKCC, Rand Corporation, and others.
  - International Atomic Energy Agency - Reports and Lectures, 1978-1980 (Box 17, Folder 4-5)
  - LSR Investments, 1950s-1976 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Investment Reports and Analysis, 1946-1980 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Lectures, 1975-1978 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Harper Woodward Pocket and Desk Calendars, 1956-1980 (Box 19)